

Albane MAGNIN

Contact



71570 La Chapelle de Guinchay



B license | 30 years old



06 21 98 41 45



magninalb@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/albanemagnin

https://github.com/AlbaneMAGNIN

https://albanemagnin.github.io/Portfolio/

Language

French : native English : CLES B2

Expertise

ReactJS SASS Javascript HTML5 PHP

IT tools

Linux GitHub Agile method Azur DevOps

Projects

Available on my GitHub account and my portfolio.

About me

After more than two years of experience as a QA in the payroll department, I was fascinated by the job of an IT developer.

In 2022, I started training to become a Web and Mobile Web Developer and obtained my professional qualification in 2023.

This transition is a natural progression based on my experience, analytical skills, passion for technology and willingness to learn.

Web developer

Experience

• June 2023 - August 2023

C.D | Star Citizen Universe

Fullstack developer - Javascript | Internships

Team of 4 fullstack developers.

Development of a website based on the Star Citizen universe, allowing access to public data from the game, management of organisations and their fleet of ships, and searching for objects with a social networking approach.

February 2023 - March 2023
O'Clock School

Front-end developer - ReactJS

Team of 4 developers: 3 front & 1 back.

Develop a comprehensive travel application for outdoor enthusiasts in France, with an interactive map showing places to stay and places to visit nearby.

March 2019 - October 2021

Full | Software editor

December 2019 - October 2021

Payroll QA Referent | Team of 3 QA

In charge of:

- Size workload for the team
- Manage deadlines
- Train and support payroll quality employees
- Same missions as those for the position of payroll quality controller

March 2019 - December 2019

Payroll QA Controller

In collaboration with lawyers, modellers and developers teams :

- Drafting, run, and validate tests to deploy in clients DB
- Drafting clients and internals documentations

• July 2018 - January 2019

Toupargel Groupe | Distribution group specialized in home grocery delivery

Payroll expert - Sage i7 & SAP

In charge of:

- Software updates, social monitoring, producing internal documents
- Manage payroll periods
- Bank transfers (wages, salary installments), statement of charges, social and accounting reporting
- November 2014 March 2018

CONSULTYS | Pharmaceutical engineering consultancy

June 2017 - March 2018

Software migration manager and replacement of the payroll social manager - Sage X3

- Migration Ciel Paie to Sage X3
 - Definition of needs, development of specifications, internal audit
 - Optimization of practices, establishment of internal procedures
 - Exchanges, meetings and training with the consulting firm
 - Start-up with respect to deadlines and provisional planning
- Payroll, personnel administration, social monitoring (200 employees); management 1 employee

November 2014 - June 2017

Payroll and personnel administration administrator

Assignements: payroll, absenteeism, personnel administration, training

Formation

• September 2022 - March 2023 O'Clock School | Professional Certificate RNCP Level 5

Web & mobile web developer, specializing in ReactJS

- 3 months learning: Javascript, PHP, Laravel, SQL, design pattern MVC, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap
- 1 month: specialization in ReactJS
- 1 month: development of the Day & Night application
- September 2013 September 2014 Université Claude Bernard Lyon 1 | Bachelor's degree Organizational management, major human relations
- September 2011 September 2013 Université Lumière Lyon 2 | University diploma Business and administration management, major human relations